# **Benjamin Perrault**

▶ benjaminperrault.com ▶ benjamin.perrault@gmail.com ♥ Tulsa, Oklahoma ♠ 918benjamin

I'm a backend-leaning full-stack software engineer based in Tulsa, Oklahoma. I have multiple years of experience in both the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Over the past 2.5 years, I've built a solid foundation in web engineering fundamentals that I'm eager to deploy on challenging projects that expand my current skill set. Most recently I co-created Nexus, a tool for generating and deploying GraphQL APIs to AWS.

# SKILLS

#### **Back End**

JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, Golang, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs, GraphQL

#### **Front End**

JavaScript (ES6), React, Jest, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Handlebars

#### **Technologies**

Git, GitHub, Docker, Bash, Terraform, DigitalOcean (VPS), AWS (EC2, Fargate, ECS, ECR)

### **{}** TECHNICAL PROJECTS

09/2022 - 12/2022

**Nexus,** Co-Creator & Software Engineer -- nexus-graphql.github.io ☑ An open-source tool that generates a GraphQL API from multiple data sources and deploys to AWS cloud infrastructure, abstracting away dozens of manual steps for fast setup.

- Led the development of a command line interface to automate GraphQL server generation, drastically reducing manual configuration (Node.js, Inquirer, Commander)
- Created a dashboard for API customization, testing, and deployment monitoring with a re-deployment notification system, hot-reloading local test server, and advanced data source configuration via GUI (React, Express, TailwindCSS)
- Resolved multi-source over-fetching and N+1 performance issues with dynamically generated custom GraphQL schema extensions and resolvers (GraphQL Mesh, YAML)
- Containerized server code for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure and automated AWS deployment and teardown (Docker, AWS CLI, Terraform, ECR, ECS Fargate)
- Authored an in-depth technical case study: nexus-graphql.github.io ☑

08/2020 - 12/2022

#### **Software Engineer**

A selection of the projects developed during my 2.5-year career transition:

- Request Cloud A database-backed webhook request inspection and debugging application (React, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, deployed to Digital Ocean Droplet)
- Airline Routes An interactive SVG map of airline routes (React, JavaScript, Node.js)
- Todo Tracker A Single Page Application backed by a PostgreSQL database (Ruby, Sinatra, ERB, SQL, Postgres)

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

03/2018 - 07/2022

**Freelance,** Marketing Consultant

- Researched, executed, and evaluated email, social, SEO, and paid media campaigns
- 8-month software project manager contract leading client-developer relationship

09/2015 - 03/2018

**Gitwit Creative,** Marketing Campaign Director

- Hired and led a team of strategists to sell, execute, and analyze client campaigns
- Assisted founders in developing internal processes as the team grew from 12 to 25

#### EDUCATION

08/2020 – 12/2022 **Launch School,** Software Engineering & Full-Stack Web Development

09/2011 – 05/2014 University of Tulsa, B.S. Business Administration & B.A. Spanish Language